Finding Aid for University of Michigan diplomas, 1845-1930s, 1977
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
University of Michigan diplomas
1845-1930s
1977
University of Michigan.
87394 Bimu C11 Outsize
Collection of diplomas issued by the University of Michigan.
13 oversize folders 180 items
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The collection was accumulated from different donors.
Periodic additions to the records expected.
The collection was accumulated from different donors.
This assembled collection consists of diplomas issued to University of Michigan students from various departments and colleges. Also included is a sample of a corrected blank form to be used in 1845 if engraved diplomas did not arrive in time.
The Diplomas collection consists of approximately 150 diplomas issued by the University of Michigan, 1845-1934, as well as some special program diplomas and certificates and seven diplomas for other institutions of higher education.
Subjects:
University of Michigan--Commencements.
Genre Terms:
Diplomas.
- Diplomas: University of Michigan
  - 1845-1849 (Folder 1)
    - Blank diploma, 1845
    - Hunt, Charles J. B.A., 1846
    - Parker, Franklin L. B.A., 1847
    - Pray, George W. B.A., 1845
    - Shaw, Horatio W. B.A., 1848
    - Tenny, Edward B.A., 1848
  - 1850-1859 (Folder 2)
    - Edmunds, James M. B.A., 1859
    - Gibbs, Galucia C. B.A., 1855
      (Diploma reads 1858 graduate catalogue says 1855)
    - Hall, Daniel M.D., 1854
    - Harter, Matthias B.S., 1855
    - Jewell, Phineas A. M.D., 1859
    - Lane, George M. B.A., 1853
    - Northrop, Byron B. B.A., 1855
    - Reynolds, Milton B.A., 1856
    - Reynolds, Milton M.A., 1859
    - Tyler, Dean M. M.D., 1859
    - Watson, James C. B.A., 1857
  - 1860-1869 (Folder 3)
    - Aikman, Robert M.D., 1868
    - Bates, Noah M.D., 1866
    - Cheever, Byron W. B.A., 1863
    - Cheever, Byron W. M.A., 1866
    - Cheever, Byron W. M.D., 1867
    - Eddy, Samuel M. Bachelor of Laws, 1869
    - Edmunds, James M. M.A., 1862
    - Edmunds, James M. Bachelor of Laws, 1863
    - Foster, George A. Bachelor of Laws, 1861
    - Guthrie, James W. M.D., 1862
    - Jackson, Amzi F. M.D., 1865
    - Kitchen, Samuel M.D., 1863
    - McMillan, Dugald M.D., 1868
    - Nichols, Henry A. Bachelor of Laws, 1862
    - Parks, Benjamin F. M.A., 1860
    - Pray, George W. M.A, 1863
    - Rose, Preston B. M.D., 1862
    - Schuyler, Peter L. M.D., 1862
    - Seymour, Christopher M.D., 1869
    - Spence, Edwin A. B.A., 1860
    - Spence, Edwin A. M.A., 1864
    - Sutfin, Edward I. Bachelor of Laws, 1868
    - Wheeler, Orlando B. B.S., 1862
    - Wilder, Flavius M. M.D., 1868
  - 1870-1879 (Folder 4)
    - Armstrong, Samuel M.D., 1877
    - Ayers, James Nelson Pharmaceutical Chemist, 1879
    - Baldwin, Albert E. B.S., 1871
    - Baldwin, Newton M.D., 1875
    - Barnes, Erastus A. Ph.B., 1879
    - Brownsberger, Sidney M.A., 1875
    - Bulkley, Fred G. Civil Engineer, 1875
    - Case, William N. M.D., 1873
    - Casper, Jason M M.D., does not appear in Alumni Catalog, 1876
    - Chamberlin, Livy Bachelor of Laws, 1879
    - Cheever, Byron W. Bachelor of Laws, 1875
    - Dingley, Charles A. Pharmaceutical Chemist, 1876
    - Douglass, William M. M.D., 1871
    - Elwood, Isaac M.A., 1870
    - Ewell, Marshall D. honorary, 1879
    - Fearon, Robert N. M.A., 1873
    - Gibson, Elbridge D. Pharmaceutical Chemist, 1878
    - Goodwin, Fairfield M.D., 1874
    - Granger, Annie B.A., 1874
    - Harley, Virginia M.D., 1873
    - Hubbard, Caroline I. B.S., 1875
    - Lodge, Albert Homeopathic M.D., 1879
    - McIlvaine, John C. M.D., 1872
      (diploma spells name "McIlrain")
    - McKimmie, William Pharmaceutical Chemist, 1870
    - Mosher, Eliza M. M.D., 1875
    - Noyes, Henry C. Bachelor of Laws, 1873
    - Pond, Irving K. Civil Engineer, 1879
    - Raymond, James H. B.A., 1878
    - Reed, Louisa M. M.S., 1877
    - Salmon, Lucy M. B.A., 1876
    - Tyler, Dean M. Bachelor of Laws, 1875
    - Waldron, Henry C. Bachelor of Laws, 1872
    - Wells, Frank B. D.D.S., 1879
    - Wheeler, Levi L. Civil Engineer, 1874
    - White, George F. Bachelor of Laws, 1876
    - Willison, Eugene Bachelor of Laws, 1874
      (Alumni Catalog gives graduation date as 1875)
    - Willson, Theodore B. B.A., 1872
    - Young, Charles Bachelor of Laws, 1877
      (does not appear in Alumni Catalog)
  - 1880-1889 (Folder 5)
    - Anderson, Edward P. Ph.D., 1886
    - Barnes, Erastus A. Ph.M., 1880
    - Bates, Joseph I. M.A., 1880
    - Brandon, Edgar E. B.A., 1888
    - Brown, Ralph W. Civil Engineer, 1881
    - Cavanaugh, Martin B.A., 1887
    - Chandler, George G. Pharmaceutical Chemist, 1880
    - Clark, Mary E. Bachelor of Letters, 1885
    - Clark, Mary E. M.D., 1887
    - Clements, Charles B.A., 1883
    - Cochran, Carlos B. M.A., 1888
    - Cooley, Mortimer E. Mechanical Engineer, 1885
    - Cramer, Seward B.S. in Civil Engineering, 1887
    - Dunn, Henry E. D.D.S., 1880
    - Evans, John S. Bachelor of Laws, 1883
    - Hill, George J. M.D., 1881
    - Hudson, William C. Bachelor of Laws, 1880
    - Jellison, Ernest R. M.D., 1883
    - Laub, J. Katherine Homeopathic M.D., 1884
    - Loveland, William L. Bachelor of Letters, 1882
    - McNaughton, Clara W. D.D.S., 1885
    - Magness, Caroline Ada D.D.S., 1886
    - Morley, Fred B.S. in Civil Engineering, 1886
    - Perkins, William T. Bachelor of Laws, 1884
    - Pond, Allen B. B.A., 1880
    - Stoddard, Thomas A. M.D., 1886
    - Walterhouse, John T. Bachelor of Laws, 1882
      (diploma misprinted "Waterhouse")
    - Whitney, Allen S. B.A., 1885
  - 1890-1899 (Folder 6)
    - Bradfield, Thomas Bachelor of Laws, 1895
    - Burt, Benjamin C. Ph.D., 1894
    - Cramer, Seward Bachelor of Laws, 1891
    - Douglas, Henry W. B.S. in Mechanical Engineering, 1890
    - Eddy, Hattie Bachelor of Letters, 1893
    - Eddy, Hattie Bachelor of Letters in the Science and the Art of Teaching and English, 1893
    - Eddy, Jennie Ph.B., 1893
      (diploma gives name as Joanna)
    - Goldthwaite, Nellie E. B.S. in Chemistry, 1894
    - Guthrie, William J. B.A., 1899
    - Guthrie, William J. B.A. in Science and the Art of Teaching and Mathematics, 1899
    - Hicks, Frederick C. Ph.D., 1890
    - King, Elsa Bachelor of Letters, 1899
    - Manny, Frank A. B.A., 1893
    - Manny, Frank A. M.A., 1896
    - Miller, Craig C. Bachelor of Laws, 1898
    - Morley, Fred Civil Engineer, 1890
    - Nicholson, Elbert B.S. in Mechanical Engineering, 1895
    - O'Brien, Frank M.A., 1894
    - O'Brien, Thomas Bachelor of Laws, 1899
      (with note "as of the Class of 1865")
    - Read, Fanny K. Bachelor of Letters in "English and The Science and Art of Teaching", 1890
    - Roth, Filibert B.S., 1890
    - Tuttle, Arthur J. Bachelor of Philosophy, 1892
    - Williams, Olney S. Bachelor of Laws, 1896
  - 1900-1909 (Folder 7)
    - Benham, Albert S. B.A., 1908
    - Manwaring, Joshua G. M.D., 1901
    - O'Brien, Thomas J. Legum Doctoris, 1908
    - Pemberton, Fantine two year degree in nursing, 1890
    - Spaulding, Thomas M. B.A., 1902
    - Stroebe, George G. B.S. in Civil Engineering, 1904
    - Travis, DeHull N. Bachelor of Laws, 1908
  - 1910-1919 (Folder 8)
    - Blair, Minerva M.D., 1912
    - Conover, Charles J. B.S., 1911
    - Fisher, Leonard P. D.D.S., 1916
    - Lehr, Clarence E. Bachelor of Laws, 1914
    - Madden, Clyde A. Pharmaceutical Chemist, 1914
    - Messerly, John M. B.A., 1912
    - Pond, Alan B. M.A., 1910
    - Rathke, Ethel A. W. M.A., 1914
    - Voorhees, Sophia M.A., 1910
  - 1920-1929 (Folder 9)
    - Benham, Albert S. Master of Science, Department of Chemistry, 1926
    - Brumbaugh, Herbert Leroy Doctoris Artis Medica, 1929
    - Cooley, Mortimer E. Doctoris Artis Mechanicae, 1929
    - Nash, Edna L. B.A., 1922
    - Roth, Filibert Legum Doctoris, 1923
    - Smith, Erwin F. Legum Doctoris, 1922
    - Tuttle, Ruth B. B.A., 1927
  - 1930-1934 (Folder 10)
    - Hinsdale, Wilbert B. M.A., 1934
    - Lombard, Warren, P. Scientiae Doctoris, 1931
    - Pond, Irving K. Architecturae Doctoris, 1930
    - Tuttle, Arthur J. Legum Magistri, 1930
  - UM Special Courses (Folder 11)
    - Brown, H. H. attended a Special Course in Electro-Therapeutics, 1885
    - Cheever, Byron W. certificate for completion of 2 full courses of Lectures regarding Chemistry and Mineralogy, 1864
    - Frissell, Seraph certificate for attendance at a "Special Course of Instruction in Physical Diagnosis", 1875
    - Kellogg, John H. certificate for attendance at a "Special Course of Instruction in Physical Diagnosis", 1874
    - Macpherson, J. attended a Special Course in the Physiological Laboratory, 1881
    - Macpherson, J. attended a Special Course in Electro-Therapeutics, 1882
    - Seymour, Christopher certificate for completion of 1 full course of Lectures regarding Chemistry and Mineralogy, 1868
    - Tyler, Dean M. certificate for completion of 1 full course of Lectures regarding Quantitative Analysis, 1858
- Diplomas: Non-University of Michigan (Folder 12)
  - Eaton, Ella E., Artinum Saurcae (?) can't figure out where, 1872
  - Kellogg, John H., 25 lesson course in Physical Diagnosis by Edward Janeway and JWS Arnold, 1875
  - Kellogg, John H., 25 lesson course in Normal and Pathological Histology by Edward Janeway and JWS Arnold, 1875
  - Marsh, Theodore D., 3 years instruction in Gospel Ministry at the Auburn Theological Seminary, 1864
  - Patterson, John C. Bachelor of Laws from the University of Albany, 1865
  - Roth, Mrs. F. Honorable Mention given by the Columbian Exposition Board of Lady Managers, 1895
  - Watson James C. honorary degree from Columbia College for the director of the Observatory, 1877
- Miscellaneous (Folder 13)
  - Eddy, Hattie, Bachelor of Letters, Teacher's Certificate, 1893
  - Manwaring, Joshua G., certificate of internship in the departments of General Medicine, Surgery, Ophthalmology, Gynecology and Obstetrics, Neurology and Dermatology, 1901
  - Manwaring, Joshua G., certificate verifying position of house physician in the departments of Internal Medicine, Surgery, Ophthalmology, Gynecology, Nervous Diseases, and Dermatology., 1902
  - Roth, Filibert, certificate of membership in Alpha Sigma Xi, 1899
  - Tuttle, Arthur J., Bachelor of Philosophy, Teacher's Diploma, 1892
  - Nixon, Evelyn Ph.D., 1977